(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
ときのそら 生誕祭 2025
Tokino Sora Birthday Party 2025
告知あり❤
Announcement included❤
新衣装お披露目
New Outfit Reveal
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday dear Sora-chan
スタースタースタート！
Stars Stars Start!
我ら星の空の始まりは (Banfire)
Our starry sky begins with a bang (Bangfire)
揺れた瞬間 あららら (Banfire)
The moment it shook, oh my (Bangfire)
あぁこれは困った
Ah, this is a problem
二度と元には戻らない 大爆発
It'll never go back, a big explosion
そして星が生まれまして (Banfire)
And then a star was born (Bangfire)
明け方の1番星は (Banfire)
The first star of dawn (Bangfire)
あなたと出会った
Meeting you
これは次元を揺るがす大発見
is a grand discovery that shakes dimensions
そのままハート打ち上げて
Keep launching your heart
どこまでも高い空までめちゃ跳んじゃいたい
I want to jump high into the sky
STAR STAR STAR ときたこのラブは
STAR STAR STAR, this love
あなたがなきゃ今頃超新星してただろう
would've gone supernova by now without you
(Ah-ah-ah) してただろう
(Ah-ah-ah) would've been
あなたへせまる
Approaching you
UNDER STANDS STANDS STANDS
ほら目の前にずっとある一等星 見てろ
Look at the first-magnitude star right in front of you
見てろ
Watch it
このビッグバンに気づいて
Notice this Big Bang
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love expands as big as the Earth, and it's like this
超・大・装・星はこの時のためのさ
The grand star decoration is for this moment
ビビビッときた あなたのハートに通知
Got a zap, a notification to your heart
暇な時でいいよみたいな顔してめちゃめちゃ大好き
Acting like it's okay when you're free, but I love you so much
ちょっとの反応くれたら喜ぶ性質
I'm the type to be happy with a little reaction
てかこれ逃すなんて嘆かわしい
It'd be deplorable to miss this
我ら星の活動は (Banfire)
Our starry activities (Bangfire)
割と続いてもうもうもう (Banfire)
Have lasted quite a while now (Bangfire)
やぁこれはすごいな
Wow, this is amazing
つまりあなたこそ私の創世記
In short, you are my Genesis
そのままハートあなたごと連れて
Taking your heart along with you
彼方をめざしてめちゃ跳んじゃった
I jumped high aiming for the distance
STAR STAR STAR としたこのラブは
STAR STAR STAR, this love
あなたがなきゃ今頃超新星してた
would've gone supernova by now without you
してたが
It would have, but
ほら今日まで続いた
look, it's continued until today
UNDER STANDS STANDS STANDS
いそこだまして輝く一等星 あなたと
The first-magnitude star shining over there, with you
私で
and me,
ビッグバンしたいの
we want to make a Big Bang
愛は地球くらいに膨らんでこんなになってんぞ
Love expands as big as the Earth, and it's like this
超・大・装・星はこの時のためにさ
The grand star decoration is for this moment
みんなー！ 今日はお誕生日ライブに来てくれて
Everyone! Thank you for coming to my birthday
ありがとうー！
live today!
最初に聴いてもらったのは、『スタースタースタート！』でしたー！
The first song you heard was 'Stars Stars Start!'
みんなコメント見えてるよー！
I can see everyone's comments!
初めましての人もいっぱいコメントしていってねー！
If you're here for the first time, feel free to leave lots of comments!
えー、最初からすごい気合を入れすぎましたね。
Wow, I put way too much energy into it right from the start.
というわけで、えー、今日、私のお誕生日です！
So, well, today is my birthday!
喉が渇きました。あ、すみません。ありがとうございます。
I'm thirsty. Oh, excuse me. Thank you.
んー。まちがーる、美味しい。
Mmm. Machi-girl (Matcha drink), delicious.
はい、というわけで、お水美味しいぞ。というわけで。
Okay, so, the water (drink) is good. Anyway.
今日のハッシュタグは、#ときのそらお披露目誕生日2025 です！
Today's hashtag is #ときのそらお披露目誕生日2025!
ぜひトレンドにも入れたいので、良ければそちらでも呟いてください。
I really want it to trend, so please tweet using it if you can.
そしてですね、新衣装のお披露目や、ゲストをたくさん呼んでいるので、
And also, I'll be showing off a new outfit and I've invited many guests,
楽しみにしててねー！ ふぅー！
so please look forward to it! Woo!
というわけで、今回はね、カウントダウンでも使われているアリーナに、
So, this time, in the arena that's also used for the countdown,
私の装飾をしてもらいました！ 超可愛いでしょー！ わぁー！
they've decorated it for me! It's super cute, right? Yay!
そして、見て！ ぬんぬんがね、
And look! Nun-Nun is...
4段になってるんです。
It's become 4 tiers.
4段になってるのは、あの、
The reason there are 4 tiers is, well...
毎年増やしてるから4段なんですね。
...it's because I add one every year.
ってことは来年は5段になるんだな。
So that means next year there'll be 5 tiers.
すごい、どんどん積み重なって行っちゃうね。
Wow, they're just gonna keep stacking up.
そして、あんきももですね、
And also, Ankimo is...
今回はホログラムでビックサイズ！
...in hologram this time, big size!
でか。本当に大きい。
Huge. It's really big.
私だけを映すと文字しか映らないっていう
It's such a big size that if you only show me,
ビッグサイズなんですよね。
you only see the letters.
お団子かな？そう、お団子なんですよ。
Is it dango? Yes, it's dango.
あ、ぬんぬんのことでしょ？
Oh, you mean Nun-nun?
ちょっとね、でも顔、文字しか、
A bit, though, only the letters...
顔がね大きくて見えないので...
the face is so big I can't see it...
あ、じゃあ、ぬんぬーーん！
Ah, then, Nun-nuuun!
あ、きた！ぬんぬんがきました。
Ah, there! Nun-nun is here.
というわけで、ぬんぬん、乗せてもらってもいいかにゃ？
So, Nun-nun, can I ride on you?
いい？
Is it okay?
うわああ！埋まってるけどね、乗るっていうより。
Waaaah! I'm buried in it, rather than riding.
あーーーい！
Aaaaay!
ということで、こちらがあんきもの顔です。
So, this is Ankimo's face.
あんきもはずっとこうやって動いてます。
Ankimo is moving like this all the time.
そして、意外とね、つぶらな瞳なんですけど...
And, surprisingly, it has round eyes...
ちょちょちょって、しっかりね、おめめになってるんですね。
Ch-ch-ch, they're properly eyes, aren't they?
素晴らしい。うん、うん。うん、うん。
Wonderful. Yeah, yeah. Yeah, yeah.
そして、あ、みんなー！見えてるよー！
And, oh, everyone! I can see you!
会場のみんな、ありがとう！
Everyone in the venue, thank you!
ありがとう！見えてるぞー！
Thank you! I can see you!
はーーい！
Haaaay!
すごい、ぬんぬんが空を飛ばせてくれました。
Amazing, Nun-nun let me fly in the sky.
いぇーい。というわけで、そんなぬんぬんが...
Yay. So, as Nun-nun...
降ろしてくれた場所は、さっきと違う場所ですね。
...let me down, it's a different place than before.
もう一回お水を飲んだら、曲に行きたいかなと思います。
I'll take another drink of water, then I'd like to go to the song.
やぁ、今日はね、ドキドキなんですよ。
Wow, I'm so nervous today.
生放送ってね、やっぱドキドキしますよね。
Live broadcasts are always nerve-wracking, aren't they?
なんか分かる？なんかね、さっきまで調子悪い調子悪いって言ってたのに...
Do you get it? Like, I was saying I wasn't feeling well just now...
今、全然調子悪くなくなっちゃった。
...but now I don't feel bad at all.
こんなだから、誰にも心配してもらえないんだ。
Because of this, nobody ever worries about me.
というわけで、次の曲行ってみましょう。
So, let's go to the next song.
2曲続けて聞いてください。
Please listen to two songs in a row.
さくらびと
Sakura-bito
作詞・作曲：石風呂
Lyrics/Composition: Ishifuro
喜びが舞う 春を
In the spring where joy dances
涙の花
Flower of tears
散りゆく花びらとなり
Becoming petals that scatter away
あなたの元へと
To where you are
風が鳴るたび そばにいるよ
Every time the wind whistles, I am by your side
たどり着けぬ悲しみより
More than the sadness I cannot reach
寂しさより
More than the loneliness
守るべきを 今を生きる
I live for what I must protect, for the now
あなた 生まれ変わったら
If you are reborn,
桜の下で また会いましょう
let's meet again under the cherry blossoms
きっとその時には笑って
Surely at that time, let's smile and
永遠を誓おう
vow for eternity
愛し愛されて この命は
Loving and being loved, this life
芽吹いて咲いて
buds and blooms
色褪せない眼差しを 胸に
With an unfading gaze in my heart,
舞い散る願い
the scattering wishes
ah あなたに
ah to you
ah あなたに 届けたい
ah to you, I want it to reach
凪いで 光は無く
Calming, the light is gone
右と左の
Right and left
翼は
wings are
キツキツ揺れてる
shaking tightly
穏やかな日々 信じながら
While believing in peaceful days
愛してると
Wanting to say
伝えたくて
"I love you"
伝えないのは 忘れてほしい
Not telling you, I want you to forget
明日を生きる ために
In order to live tomorrow
生まれ変わったら
If we are reborn,
桜の下で また会いましょう
let's meet again under the cherry blossoms
待ち焦がれた季節の中で
In the season we've been waiting for,
共に歩こう
let's walk together
この心を染め抜いた花よ あなたに届け
Oh flower that dyed this heart, reach out to you
誇り高き 潔さで 名もなき風に
With high pride and purity, to the nameless wind
大切なものは いつの時代も
The important things, no matter the era,
変わらないことを
are things that don't change
人は知りながら 過ちを
Even though people know this, mistakes...
なぜ繰り返す
...why do they repeat them?
生まれ変わったら 桜の下で また会いましょう
If we are reborn, let's meet again under the cherry blossoms
きっとその時には笑って 永遠を誓おう
Surely at that time, we'll smile and vow eternity
愛し愛されてこの命は 芽吹いて咲いて
Loving and being loved, this life buds and blooms
色褪せない眼差しを胸に
With unfading eyes in my heart,
舞い散る願い
wishes dance and fall
はぁ あなたに
Ah, to you
届けたくて
Wanting to reach you
はぁ あなたに
Ah, to you
届けたくて
Wanting to reach you
命に嫌われている。
Hated by Life Itself
「死にたい」なんて言うなよ。
Don't say things like "I want to die."
「諦めないで生きろ」よ。
"Live without giving up."
そんな歌が正しいなんて馬鹿げてるよな。
It's ridiculous to think songs like that are right.
実際自分は死んでもよくて
In reality, I don't mind if I die,
周りが死んだら悲しくて
but I'd be sad if those around me did
それが嫌だからっていうエゴなんです。
It's just an ego that says "because I hate that."
他人が生きててもどうでもよくて
I don't care if others live,
誰かを嫌うこともファッションで
and hating someone is just a fashion
それでも「平和に生きよう」なんて素敵なことでしょう。
Yet "let's live in peace" - isn't that a wonderful thing?
画面の先では誰かが死んで
On the other side of the screen, someone dies.
それを嘆いて誰かが歌って
Someone sings, mourning that.
それに感化された少年が
Influenced by that, a boy...
ナイフを持って走った。
...ran with a knife.
僕らは命に嫌われている。
We are hated by life itself.
価値観もエゴも押し付けて
Pushing values and egos,
いつも誰かを殺したい歌を
always a song that wants to kill someone...
簡単に電波で流した。
...was easily sent over the airwaves.
僕らは命に嫌われている。
We are hated by life itself.
軽々しく「死にたい」だとか
Lightly saying "I want to die"
軽々しく命を見てる
or looking at life lightly...
僕らは命に嫌われている。
...we are hated by life itself.
お金がないので今日も
Having no money, today too
一日中惰眠を謳歌する
I enjoy idleness all day long
生きる意味なんて見出せず
Unable to find a meaning to live,
無駄を自覚して息をする
I breathe while conscious of the futility
言葉でこの傷が表せていいものか
Could these words possibly express this wound?
そんな意地ばかり抱え今日も一人ベッドに眠る
Holding onto such stubbornness, I sleep alone in bed again today.
少年だった僕たちはいつか青年に変わっていく
We who were boys will someday change into young men.
年老いていつか枯葉のように誰にも知られず朽ちていく
Getting older, someday like withered leaves, we'll rot away unknown to anyone.
不死身の体を手に入れて一生死なずに生きてゆく
Obtaining an immortal body, living forever without dying.
そんなSFを妄想してる
I'm daydreaming about such science fiction.
自分が死んでもどうでもよくて
I don't care if I die,
それでも周りに生きて欲しくて
But I still want those around me to live.
矛盾を抱えて生きてくなんて怒られてしまう
Living while holding such contradictions, I'd surely be scolded.
「正しいものは正しくいなさい」
“Let what is right be right.”
「死にたくないなら生きていなさい」
“If you don't want to die, then live.”
悲しくなるならそれでもいいならずっと一人で笑えよ
If that makes you sad, and if you're fine with that, then just laugh alone forever.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福の意味すらわからず
Without even understanding the meaning of happiness,
生まれた環境ばかり憎んで
Just hating the environment we were born into,
簡単に過去ばかり呪う
Easily cursing our pasts.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
さよならばかりが過ぎすぎて
Too many goodbyes have passed us by,
本当の別れなど知らない
Without knowing what a real parting is like.
僕らは命に嫌われている
We are hated by life itself.
幸福も別れも愛情も友情も
Happiness, partings, love, and friendship,
滑稽な夢の戯れで全部カネで買える代物
In a ridiculous dream's play, they're all things that can be bought with money.
明日死んでしまうかもしれない
We might die tomorrow.
すべて無駄になるかもしれない
Everything might become wasted.
朝も夜も春も秋も変わらず誰かがどこかで死ぬ
Morning, night, spring, and autumn, someone dies somewhere without fail.
夢も明日も何もいらない
I don't need dreams or tomorrow or anything.
君が生きていたならそれでいい
As long as you're alive, that's enough.
そうだ、本当はそういうことが歌いたい
That's right, honestly, that's the kind of thing I want to sing.
命に嫌われている
Hated by life itself.
結局いつかは死んでゆく
In the end, we'll die eventually.
君だって僕だっていつかは枯葉のように朽ちてく
You too, me too, will someday rot away like withered leaves.
それでも僕らは必死に生きて
Even so, we live desperately,
命を必死に抱えて生きて
Clinging desperately to life as we live,
殺してあがいて笑って抱えて
Killing, struggling, laughing, holding on,
生きて、生きて、生きて、生きて、生きろ
Live, live, live, live, stay alive!
はい！ということで、今聴いてもらったのは
Alright! So, what you just heard were
「サクラカゼ」と「命に嫌われている。」でした！
“Sakura Kaze” and “Hated by Life Itself!”
わー、緊張しすぎて、ちょっと何回か噛んじゃった。
Wow, I was so nervous that I stumbled over my words a few times.
リハの方が声出てたよ、絶対に。ね？そう思うでしょ？
I definitely sang better during rehearsal. Right? Don't you think so?
画面の皆さーん！え？
Everyone watching! Huh?
わー！今トレンド2位なの？
Wow! I'm trending at number two right now?
みんなありがとーーー！
Thank you everyone!
急なテンションの差にビビらないで。ねぇ？ねぇ？
Don't be startled by the sudden change in mood. Okay? Okay?
めちゃめちゃよかった？「わんこ」って言わないで。
It was really good? Don't call me 'wanko' (puppy).
私、犬じゃないんだ。わん！
I'm not a dog. Woof!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい。落差がすごい。ね、落差すごいよね。
Yes. The gap is huge. Right? It's a huge gap.
いぇーい！でもさ、まだまだライブは始まったばっかりよ！
Yay! But the live concert has only just begun!
今日初めて見に来ましたよー！って人、ぜひ楽しんでってねー！
For those of you who came to see me for the first time today, please enjoy yourselves!
いぇーい！ご機嫌。
Yay! I'm in high spirits.
というわけで、早速次はゲストパートに行っちゃおうかな！へへっ。
So, let's head right into the guest section! Hehe.
最初のゲストは、この人だ！
The first guest is... this person!
GUEST 緋月ゆい
GUEST Hizuki Yui
はい！ということで、最初のゲストは、ゆいちゃんです！
Alright! So, our first guest is Yui-chan!
ゆいたーーーん！
Yui-taaan!
そらさー…
Sora-san...
ちょっと待って、声やば…
Wait, my voice is terrible...
そらさー、声やばい…
Sora-san, my voice is so bad...
エグい、エグい声してるけど、誕生日おめでとうございます！
My voice is awful, but Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
すいません、本当にもう、この度は…
I'm so sorry, about this time...
この度は本当にもう、誠に申し訳ございませんでした。
I'm truly, deeply sorry for this.
ちょっとよくなってきた？
Is it getting any better?
え？なんですか？
Eh? What was that?
ちょっと待って、声出ない。
Wait a sec, no voice is coming out.
リハーサルの時の方が声出てた。何があったの、
Your voice was better during rehearsal. What happened,
この数日間で。
over the last few days?
なんか良くなるどころか、悪くなってきましたねこれ。
It's actually getting worse instead of better.
お大事に…
Please take care...
ということでね、体調をね、ちょっとね。
So, your health isn't great right now.
体調というか、喉をね。
Well, specifically your throat.
咳が止まらなくなってしまって、本当に申し訳ないです。
My coughing just won't stop, I'm so sorry.
こんな晴れ舞台にお誘いいただいたのに、本当に申し訳ないです。
You invited me to such a grand stage, and I'm so sorry.
ということでね、本当は今日一緒に歌う予定だったんですけど。
So, we were actually planning to sing together today.
あー歌いたかったー！
Ah, I wanted to sing so much!
そうなんですよ。次に歌う曲なんですけど、
That's right. For the next song,
『限りなく灰色へ』という曲を歌おうと思ったんですけど。
we were going to sing 'Kagirinaku Haiiro e'.
練習したんですよー！うわぁー！
I practiced for it! Uwaaah!
あのね、去年さ、3Dになったじゃん、ゆうちゃんが。
You see, Yuu-chan got her 3D model last year.
で、ずっと去年も呼ぼうと思ってたんだけど、去年はまだ3Dじゃなくて。
I wanted to invite her then, but she wasn't 3D yet.
で、結成した時からずっとずっとコラボしたいと思ってて、
Since we first met, I've always wanted to collab,
今年の誕生日にはゆうちゃんを呼ぼうってすごい決めて。
and I was determined to invite her for this birthday.
そんなに思ってくださってたのに、私は何をしてるんだ！
You thought of me that much, and yet, what am I doing!
で、そのゆうちゃんにも合いそうな曲と思ってこの曲を選んだんですよね。
And I chose this song because I thought it'd suit her.
私のために選んでくださったのに、何してんだ…バカ野郎…
You picked it for me, and I... I'm such an idiot...
でも、この状態でおしゃべりだけでも出てくれるのはとっても嬉しいから！
But even just having you here to chat like this makes me so happy!
いやもうむしろ、こんなただおしゃべりだけのために参加させていただいて、
On the contrary, for letting me participate just to chat,
本当にありがとうございます。
thank you so very much.
本当におめでとうございます！
And a very Happy Birthday to you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
だからさ、今度なんか、配信とかじゃなくて動画とか一緒に作ったりしようか。
So, instead of a stream, how about we make a video together sometime?
歌ってみたとか。
Like a cover song video.
今回のリベンジみたいな感じでさ。
It'll be like a revenge match for this time.
えっ、いいんですか？やりたいです！
Eh, is that okay? I'd love to!
やろう！
Let's do it!
やりたいです！
I want to!
やったー！
Yay!
みんなも見たいよね！見たいよね？
Everyone wants to see it, right? Right?
ペチペチ音が聞こえる。ほっぺペチペチしてました。
I hear patting sounds. I was patting my cheeks.
あ、そっちのペチペチか。コラって。
Oh, that kind of patting. Hey, now.
本当にこの出演ありがとうございます。嬉しい、本当に。
Thank you so much for coming. I'm really happy.
いやもう、歌が良すぎて、
Your singing was just too good,
私ゲスト出る前ちょっと感極まりそうだった。
I was almost moved to tears before my turn.
さっき歌われてた歌が良すぎて。
The song you just sang was incredible.
本当に？本番の方が良かったかな。
Really? I think the live version was better.
え、もうめちゃくちゃ素敵でした！
Eh, it was absolutely wonderful!
やったーやったー！
Yay, yay!
ということでね、次の曲、二人用なんですけど、
So, for the next song, it's meant for two people,
一人で頑張って歌おうと思うので、ぜひ。
but I'll do my best to sing it solo, so please listen.
応援しています！
I'll be rooting for you!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張ってください。すいません本当に。
Good luck. And again, I'm so sorry.
また一緒に遊ぼうね。
Let's hang out again soon.
はい、ぜひ！ありがとうございました、本当に。
Yes, definitely! Thank you so much.
引き続きサイリウム振って見守ってます。
I'll keep waving my penlight and watching over you.
やったー！
Yay!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
また一緒に話そうね。
Let's talk again soon.
はい、失礼します。
Yes, signing off now.
ありがとうございましたー！頑張ってください！
Thank you so much! Good luck!
またねー！
See ya!
あ、消えちゃった。消えちゃった。
Ah, she's gone. She disappeared.
というわけで、まさかの一人で歌います。
So, unexpectedly, I'll be singing this solo.
聞いてください。『限りなく灰色へ』。
Please listen. 'Kagirinaku Haiiro e'.
才能なんてないから ここで一生泣いているんだろう
Since I have no talent, I'll probably cry here forever
目に映った景色の青さが 羨ましく思ってた
The blue in the scenery I saw, I felt envious of it
路傍に転がる人生 アスファルトの温度下がってる
A life rolling by the roadside, asphalt temperature dropping
真夜中を照らす灯りを求め つなぐ電波世界へと
Seeking light to illuminate the midnight, into the connected digital world
Rainy Rainy 求めるものだけ描いた
Rainy Rainy, I drew only what I sought
心閉まって待って 本当は叫びたいのよ
Locking my heart away and waiting, honestly, I want to scream
Rainy Rainy 強くありたいと願った
Rainy Rainy, I wished to be strong
声は無情に…
My voice heartlessly...
...ちて
...and fall,
孤独を奏でる
playing my loneliness.
指先から
From my fingertips,
伝わってく
it's being transmitted,
虚ろな色
this hollow color.
認めてはくれないの？
Won't you acknowledge me?
燻んでしまったの灰色に
I've become dull and turned grey.
こんな才能なんて借り物
This kind of talent is just borrowed.
まだ人生終わってないから
Because my life isn't over yet.
「諦めるな」って誰かの声
A voice says, "Don't give up."
見失ってしまったの灰色に
I've lost sight of it in the grey.
気付けなくて今も抗ってる
I didn't realize it, so I'm still resisting.
この感情奪って去ってよ
Take this emotion and leave.
ドロドロになってしまう前に
Before everything turns into a mess.
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye to this kind of world.
滲む思いなぞって描いた
I traced my blurred thoughts and drew them.
夢の形に泣いちゃった
I ended up crying at the shape of my dreams.
いつかできると思ってた
I thought I could do it someday.
だけど現実は残酷だろ
But reality is cruel, isn't it?
焦りと不安の渦の間に
Between the vortex of impatience and anxiety,
黒くなって浮かんでる
I'm floating, turning black.
退廃的なセンスと
With a decadent sense and
曖昧な表現なんかじゃ
ambiguous expressions,
奇を衒った奴らのアリスに
I'll be swallowed by the eccentricity
飲み込まれて消えていく
of those others and disappear.
Rainy Rainy あれば流れていく徒花
Rainy, rainy, fleeting flowers flowing away.
肩を濡らして残った
Wetting my shoulders, what remains
冷たい記憶の体温
is the temperature of cold memories.
Rainy Rainy 雲の隙間から覗いた
Rainy, rainy, I peered through the gaps in the clouds.
光当たって届いて
The light hit me and reached me,
体を軽くしたんだ
making my body feel lighter.
美学とか
Aesthetics or
プライドとか
pride,
語る前に
before talking about them,
やれることやっていけ
just do what you can.
尖ってしまったの灰色に
I've become sharp and turned grey.
焼けた才能を一つ置いてけ
Leave behind one burnt talent.
ただやったもん勝ちなんでしょう
It's just a matter of who does it first, right?
片腹痛い場合じゃないでしょう
This is no time for ridiculous excuses.
目を開いてまだ変わらぬ灰色に
Open your eyes to the still unchanging grey.
気付いたってどうしようもないから
Even if I realize it, there's nothing I can do.
それを越したんだと狙ってる
I'm aiming to surpass that.
ペルソナになって越されんなよ
Become a persona and don't let them pass you.
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye to this kind of world.
滲む思いなぞって描いた
I traced my blurred thoughts and drew them.
言の葉の意味飲み込んで
Swallowing the meaning of those words.
燻んでしまったの灰色に
I've become dull and turned grey.
こんな才能なんて借り物
This kind of talent is just borrowed.
まだ人生終わってないから
Because my life isn't over yet.
「諦めるな」って誰かの声
A voice says, "Don't give up."
見失ってしまったの灰色に
I've lost sight of it in the grey.
気付けなくて今も抗ってる
I didn't realize it, so I'm still resisting.
この感情奪って去ってよ
Take this emotion and leave.
ドロドロになってしまう前に
Before everything turns into a mess.
私だけ見て愛を伝えて
Look only at me and convey your love.
こんな世界とバイバイバイバイ
Say bye-bye to this kind of world.
滲む思いなぞって描いた
I traced my blurred thoughts and drew them.
夢の形笑っていた
I was smiling at the shape of my dreams.
はい、皆さんありがとうございましたー！
Yes, thank you everyone!
1回1回お水を飲まないと、息が切れてしまいますな。
I have to drink water after every song or I'll run out of breath.
いや、あにゃいじゃない...
No, it's not "Anyai"...
反応してしまった。「はーい」って。
I ended up responding with a "Yes!".
いやぁ、というわけで、ゲストまだまだ見たいよね？
Well, you still want to see more guests, right?
ということで、どんどん行っちゃいましょうか。
So, let's keep things moving.
続いてのゲストはこの人です！
The next guest is this person!
GUEST 富士葵
GUEST Fuji Aoi
白い薔薇の花びら 1つ2つ開けば
As one or two white rose petals open,
あの日の記憶 蘇るでしょう
the memories of that day will surely be revived.
安らぎに照らされて 花を咲かせた夜は
Illuminated by peace, on nights when the flowers bloomed,
甘く切なく 色付いてゆく
they sweeten and sadden, gaining their colors.
光る糸たどるように
As if following a glowing thread,
時は静かに流れて
time flows quietly.
満ち引く揺れに沿いながら
While following the ebb and flow,
人は生まれ変わる
people are reborn.
あなたの微笑みは胸を溶かす
Your smile melts my heart.
ぬくもりどこかで見た
A warmth I've seen somewhere...
淡い夢のように
...like a fleeting dream.
沈む夕日に今を切り取られても
Even if the present is cut off by the setting sun,
二人の影は重なっていく
our shadows will overlap.
果てしなく遠く 限りなく深く
Endlessly far, infinitely deep,
交わった運命のように
like the intertwined fates.
何度も掴んで 何度も失って
Having grabbed many times, lost many times,
やっと巡り会えたこと
and finally met again.
空が地を求め 花が雨を待ち
Like the sky seeking the earth, flowers waiting for rain,
夜が明日を請うように
and the night begging for tomorrow...
二つの心が一つだったこと
...our two hearts were one.
こんなにも求めてたの
I've been searching for this so much.
長い眠り解いて 今宵巡り会えたら
Unraveling the long sleep, if we meet tonight,
二人のロンドさあ踊りましょう
it's our rondo, let's dance.
過ぎた日々を流すように
As if washing away the days that have passed,
月は優しく潤んで
the moon is gently misty.
記憶の先にもう一度
Once again, beyond memory,
愛しさが溢れた
affection overflowed.
あなたの面影を伝い歩めるなら
If I can walk along the path of your memory...
嵐が迷う風 二人を遠ざけても
Even if a storm's straying wind keeps us apart,
信じることを忘れないで
don't forget to believe.
あせない煌めき はかない揺らめき
Unfading glitter, fleeting flicker,
漂う幻のように
like a drifting illusion.
彷徨いながらも 変わらない場所へ
Even while wandering, to an unchanging place,
やっとたどり着いたこと
finally having arrived.
闇が陽を奪い 嘘が罪になり
Even if darkness takes the sun, lies become sins,
過去が未来を裂いても
and the past tears the future...
巡り行くように きっとこの場所を
...like they circulate, I would have chosen
私は選んでいたの
this place for sure.
みんな、盛り上がっていこうね！
Everyone, let's get hyped!
コメントもたくさんありがとうございます！
Thank you for all the comments!
果てしなく遠く 限りなく深く
Endlessly far, infinitely deep,
交わった運命のように
like the intertwined fates.
何度も掴んで 何度も失って
Having grabbed many times, lost many times,
やっと巡り会えたこと
and finally met again.
空が地を求め 花が雨を待ち
Like the sky seeking the earth, flowers waiting for rain,
夜が明日を請うように
and the night begging for tomorrow...
二つの心が一つだったこと
...our two hearts were one.
こんなにも求めてたの
I've been searching for this so much.
白いバラの花びら 一つ二つ散る時
When the white rose petals fall one by one,
優しい朝に染められるでしょう
they will be colored by the gentle morning.
時を経て生まれ変わって
Reborn after time,
あなたの胸に咲けば
if they bloom in your heart,
二人の愛は永遠になる
our love will be eternal.
はい！ということで！
Yes! So!
二人目のゲストは葵ちゃんだよー！
The second guest is Aoi-chan!
皆さん、富士葵です。こんばんは！
Everyone, I'm Fuji Aoi. Good evening!
そらちゃん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Sora-chan, happy birthday!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
呼んでくれてありがとう。
Thank you for inviting me.
ずっと呼びたくて！
I've been wanting to invite you!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんかさ、コラボとかはしてるけど、
You know, we've done collabs and all, but
こういう風に一緒にやるのは、あれだよね。
doing something together like this...
2年前の私の記念配信以来？
...it's been since my anniversary stream two years ago?
100万人の！
The one million subscribers one!
そうそうそうそう。
Right, right, right, right.
だから、しかも二人で歌うのは相当久しぶりじゃない？
So, and besides, singing together as a duo
is quite a while since the last time, right?
もっと前だよ！
It was even before that!
もっと前だよね。
Even before that, right.
ああ、懐かしいって感じがする。
Ah, it feels so nostalgic.
ちょっとさ、何？ネイル見せよう。
Wait, what? Let's show our nails.
ネイル？
Nails?
青です。
It's blue.
紫です。
It's purple.
頑張って塗ったよ。
I worked hard on painting them.
ねえ、おしゃれしたよ。
Yeah, we dressed up.
ねー。
Right.
やあ、あの、あんきももね、積み上がって、あんきもじゃないや。
Well, um, Ankimo is also piled up... not Ankimo.
ぬんぬん。あんきもは1匹。
Nun-nun. There's only one Ankimo.
ぬんぬんも積み上がってますけれども。
Nun-nun is also piled up, though.
おおー。
Ohh.
ま、2017年から、
Well, since 2017...
8年目？
it's the 8th year?
そうだね。
That's right.
になって、あおいね、数えたんですよ。
...now, so Aoi counted them.
そらちゃんとの共演を。
My performances with Sora-chan.
おっ。
Oh.
あの、生放送の雑談コラボとか、
Not counting things like talk collaborations...
そういうのはなしで。
...on livestreams.
おん。
Mm-hm.
31回！
31 times!
そんなにやってる！？わあー！
We've done that many?! Wow!
でも、あおい調べだから、
But that's just according to Aoi's research...
ちょっとわかんないけど。
...so I'm not sure.
やってるやってる。あってるあってる。ざっくりそんな感じだった。
We have, we have. You're right. It was roughly like that.
すごい。
Amazing.
本当にね、や、だから配信とかさ、
Truly, so if we include streams...
100万人のお祝いとかも入れたら...
...or the 1 million celebration...
もう、もっともっともっと、一緒にやらせていただいてるな。
...we've done even more and more together.
ねー。
Right.
バディだからさ、私たち、私たちバディだから。
Because we're buddies, we're buddies.
8年目だから、あおいの顔もだんだんこう、
Since it's the 8th year, I wonder if Aoi's face will...
ぬんぬんと一緒に積み上げてくれないかな？
...eventually be piled up along with Nun-nun?
怖い怖い。
Scary, scary.
隣とかでいいから。
Even just next to him is fine.
や、すごいね。だって、もう歴史がさ、ステージにも散りばめられていて。
Yeah, it's amazing. I mean, the history is scattered all over the stage.
ねえ。
Right.
すごいでしょ？めっちゃぬんぬん浮いてるの。
Isn't it great? There are so many Nun-nuns floating.
星もあるし。
And stars too.
これ、4つ、そっか、4つ4つ。
These four... I see, four, four.
あんきももね、ちゃんとあの曲のリズムに沿って
Ankimo is also moving along...
こうやってやってるんだよ。
...with the rhythm of the songs.
すごい。
Amazing.
ゆっくりになったりとか、
Going slow...
早くなったりとか。
...then fast.
あんきもも頑張ってるなーと思って。
I thought, "Ankimo is working hard too."
そう、あんきもめっちゃ頑張ってくれる。
Yeah, Ankimo is working really hard.
どうですか？誕生日の気分。
How does it feel? The birthday mood.
いや、もうなんかね、さっきまでめっちゃドキドキしてたんだけど...
Well, um, I was really nervous until just a moment ago, but...
今はこうやってみんなにこう、お祝いされて、めっちゃ嬉しい。
Now that I'm being celebrated by everyone like this, I'm so happy.
みんなたくさんコメントしてってね！
Everyone, please leave lots of comments!
すごいよ、もう、そらちゃんへの愛がね、
It's amazing, the love for Sora-chan...
そらともさんのそらちゃんへの愛がもう...
...the Soratomos' love for Sora-chan is just...
あおちゃんとはバディで！
Aoi-chan and I are buddies!
コメントからよろしくお願いします。
Please keep the comments coming.
いっぱいコメントしてよ。
Leave lots of comments.
いっぱい呟いてよ。
Tweet lots too.
よろしく。
Thank you.
あおいもこのあとも見守ってるからね！
Aoi will be watching over you for the rest of the show too!
やったー！
Yay!
また遊ぼうね。
Let's play again.
あ、あと新衣装ね。
Oh, and the new outfit.
あ、楽しみにしてるから。
Ah, I'm looking forward to it.
遊ぼうね。
Let's hang out.
遊ぼ。
Let's hang.
またねー！
See ya!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
頑張って！
Good luck!
じゃあね。
Bye-bye.
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
というわけで、相変わらず仲良しのあおちゃんでした！
So, that was Aoi-chan, we're as close as ever!
それでは続いてのゲストに行きましょう。
Now then, let's move on to the next guest.
続いてのゲストは...
The next guest is...
この人です！
...this person!
彩音
Ayane
信じてた 信じられた
I believed, I was believed in
その全てを 今始めよう
Let's start it all now
不器用な この勇気は
This clumsy courage is...
コンプレックス・イマージュ
...a "Complex Image"
乾いた風が
The dry wind...
追いかける波のように
...like the waves that chase
そっと背中を
...I felt it gently...
押す気がした
...push my back
耳を澄ませば
If you listen closely...
ざわめくレクイエム
...a noisy requiem
新しい その場所への
Throw open the door...
扉を 開け放て
...to that new place
切なくて 愛しいほど
So painful yet dear...
思いは時空を超えて
...my feelings transcend time and space
Together ずっと
Together, always...
心はそばにある
...our hearts are side by side
大切な あの陽だまりが
That precious sunny spot...
刹那に 散りゆく景色
...a scene scattering in an instant
今 全て
Now, grant...
力を 与えたまえ
...all the power
僕は 瞳を
I, without...
逸らさずに
...looking away
傷も
The wounds...
涙も
...the tears...
真実も
...and the truth
あたたかい その雫が
If that warm drop
透明なら 力となり
Is transparent, it becomes power
もしそれが 真紅ならば
But if it is crimson,
コンプレックスイマージュ
Complex Image
手探りの道
On this fumbling path
絡み合うラビリンス
This intertwining labyrinth
離れていても聴こえる声
I can hear your voice even if we're apart
目には見えない
An invisible
確かなプロフェシー
Certain prophecy
もう二度と迷わないと誓える
I can swear I'll never lose my way again
この想い
With these feelings
遙かなる社（やしろ）の神よ
O gods of the distant shrine
祈りがもし届くなら
If my prayer should reach you
震えた心に
To my trembling heart
僅かな微笑みを
Give a slight smile
戸惑いはもう何も無く
All confusion is now gone
導く光のままに
Just as the guiding light dictates
いま全ての哀しみ
Now, all the sadness
押し捨てて
Push it aside and discard it
僕は瞳をそらさずに
I will not look away
傷も涙も真実も
The wounds, the tears, and the truth too
切なくて 愛おしいほど
So painful, it's almost lovely
想いは時空（とき）を越えて
Feelings cross through space and time
Together ずっと心はそばにある
Together, our hearts are always side by side
大切な あの陽だまりが
That precious sunny spot
刹那に散りゆく景色
The scenery scattering in a fleeting moment
いま全ての力を
Now, all the power
与えたまえ
Grant me
僕は瞳をそらさずに
I will not look away
傷も涙も真実も
The wounds, the tears, and the truth too
Hey! 聴いていただいたのは、コンプレックスイマージュでしたー！
Hey! That was "Complex Image"!
そしてゲストに来ていただきました、彩音さんでーす！
And here is our guest, Ayane-san!
彩音です！
I'm Ayane!
そらとも（そら友）の皆さん、初めまして。彩音です！
Hello everyone, "Soratomo". I'm Ayane! Nice to meet you.
今日来ていただいて本当に本当にありがとうございます！
Thank you so, so much for coming today!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
嬉しすぎて、もうテンションがパーって上がってしまっていますが...
I'm so happy, my excitement is just through the roof, but...
私もです！
Me too!
本当ですか！
Really?!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
今回彩音さんに来ていただいたのは、えーっと私、なんと恐れ多くも...
The reason I invited Ayane-san today is, well, I...
...なんかコンプレックスイマージュをカバーさせていただきまして...
...humbly covered "Complex Image" and...
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
...それに反応していただいたのがとても嬉しくて...
...I was so happy that you reacted to it...
是非是非コラボで歌わせていただけたら嬉しいなと思って、お呼びいたしました！
...and I really wanted to sing it together in a collaboration, so I invited you!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you so much!
本当に来てくれるなんて思ってなくて。
I never thought you'd actually come.
今ドキドキが止まらないんですけども...
My heart won't stop racing right now...
私もです！
Me too!
今すごい心拍数が上がってます！
My heart rate is way up right now!
本当に本当にもう素敵なお声で、もう...
Truly, truly, you have such a wonderful voice that...
...私ずっとこうやって聴いてようかなって途中から思っちゃいました。
...halfway through, I thought I'd just stay like this and listen.
いやいや、一緒に歌っていただいてありがとうございます！
No, no, thank you for singing it with me!
やぁ、なんかライブでこういう風に一緒に歌えるとは思ってなかったんですけど...
Wow, I didn't think we'd be able to sing together like this at a live concert...
ど、どうでしょう。こういう大きいステージで...
W-what do you think? Singing on such a big stage...
...一緒に歌うのは。
...together?
嬉しいです！
I'm happy!
あのー、そらさんは横浜アリーナが目標なんですよね？
Um, Sora-san, your goal is Yokohama Arena, right?
はい！そうです！
Yes! That's right!
いつか、その夢が叶った時に、ご一緒できたら嬉しいです！
When that dream comes true one day, I'd be happy to join you again!
え！いいんですか！？いいんですか！？
Eh! Is that okay?! Really?!
来てください！お願いします！
Please come! I'm counting on you!
また歌ってくれるんですか？
Will you really sing with me again?
はい、もちろんっです。
Yes, of course.
とっても嬉しいです。
I'm very happy.
もう本当に、ずっとずっと聞いていた曲で、
It's a song I've really listened to forever,
他の曲もめちゃくちゃ聴いているので。
and I listen to your other songs a lot too.
嬉しいです。ありがとうございます。
I'm glad. Thank you.
本当ありがとうございます。
Thank you so much.
本当にもう大好きな方に、この生誕祭に来て頂けて、
I'm so glad someone I love came to this birthday,
もう私、感謝いっぱいです。
I'm just full of gratitude.
今後ともよろしくお願いします。
I look forward to working with you.
あ、今後ともぜひよろしくお願いします。
Oh, I look forward to it as well.
また、なんかコラボとかできたらとっても嬉しいなと思います。
I'd be so happy if we could collaborate again.
ぜひ、よろしくお願いします。
By all means, let's do it.
よろしくお願いします。
I look forward to it.
改めて、そらさんお誕生日おめでとうございます！
Once again, happy birthday, Sora-san!
ありがとうございますー！
Thank you so much!
ということで、本日は彩音さんに来て頂きました！
And so, Ayane-san joined us today!
本当に、本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you so, so much!
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
緊張した...
I was so nervous...
緊張したよー...
みんなにも緊張が伝わってたよね。
You could tell I was nervous, right?
緊張もうまく言えない、今...
I can't even say "nervous" properly now...
あ！トレンド１位になったの！？
Oh! We're #1 on trending?!
どうしよう...
What should I do...
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
というわけで、あのお誕生日配信も、
And so, this birthday stream...
終盤に近づいてきたんですけども...
is nearing its end, but...
えっと...
Um...
いや、感無量すぎて何も言えない...
No, I'm too overwhelmed to say anything...
でも、まだまだ...
But there's still...
先があるよね！
more to come!
みんな新衣装、見たいよね！
Everyone wants to see the new outfit, right!
というわけで、新衣装お披露目の時間だよー！
So, it's time for the new outfit reveal!
みんな準備はいい！？
Is everyone ready?!
いくよー！なんなら、声が...
Here we go! Actually, my voice...
へへへ。
Hehehe.
へへへ、へへへ。
Hehehe, hehehe.
いぇーい！ふー！あはは。
Yay! Woo! Ahaha.
どう？ちょっと見えた？ちょっと見えた？
How is it? Did you see a bit? Did you see a bit?
ちょっと見えたよねー！
You saw a bit, right!
手しか見えないか。
You can only see my hands.
さあ、おめでとう、みんなありがとう。
Now, happy birthday... thank you, everyone.
みんな見たーい！って言って！
Everyone, say "We want to see it!"
せーの！
One, two!
もっともっと、見たーい！
More, more, "We want to see it!"
聞こえないぞー、見たーい！
I can't hear you! "We want to see it!"
あ、素晴らしい、みんな！
Oh, wonderful, everyone!
ではいきますよ！３、２、１、オープン！
Then, here we go! 3, 2, 1, open!
はい、ということで、どうかな？今回の新衣装です！
Yes, so, how is it? This is my new outfit!
なんとね、これね、あの、テーマを書いてもらえてて。
Actually, for this, I had a theme written for it.
なんだと思う？テーマ。
What do you think the theme is?
読みますね。モノトーン絶対領域パンツ！
I'll read it. Monotone Absolute Territory Pants!
どういうこと！？どういうこと！？
What does that mean?! What does that mean?!
というわけで、今回はですね、ちょっとショートヘアに憧れちゃいまして、
So, this time, I longed for short hair a bit,
私、ちょっとショートヘアのウィッグを、手に入れちゃいました！
and I've gotten a short hair wig!
どう？ショートヘア初めてだから、ちょっと緊張してるんだけど...
How is it? It's my first time, so I'm a bit nervous...
似合うかな？似合うかな？
Does it suit me? Does it suit me?
どういうこと？なんてテーマだ。たぶん、
What does it mean? What a theme. I think...
これが絶対領域ってことなんじゃないかな。
this is what's called "absolute territory."
でね、他にもいろんなものがあるんですけど、
And, there are various other things too,
それは配信後のアフターライブメンバー限定で見せちゃおうかなって思ってるから、
but I'm showing those in the members-only after-live,
ぜひそっちも見たいなーっていう人はメン限に来てくれると嬉しいよ。
so I'd be happy if you'd join the members-only stream.
というわけで、
And so,
新衣装で歌っていこうかなって思います！
I'm thinking of singing in my new outfit!
ショート似合ってるかな？ドキドキしちゃう。
Does the short hair look good? I'm getting nervous.
いきますよ！
Here we go!
『エレクトリカル・サーフィン』！
"Electrical Surfin"!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン
Electrical Surfin'
みんな！
Everyone!
サーフィンサーフィンとか、
If you know the "surfin' surfin'"
ジャンプとか知ってる人は、
or the jumps and stuff,
一緒に言ってね！
join in with me!
攻略電子の海は今日も
In the conquerable electronic sea, today too,
晴れ時々雪所によりパフェ
it's sunny, sometimes snowy, with local parfaits
前人未到のテルライトで
With an unprecedented tell-light,
またどこかのあなたを待機中
I'm on standby for you somewhere again
偶然だって必然のうち
Even coincidences are part of inevitability,
以心伝心は見えない糸でしょ
telepathy is an invisible thread, right?
万全こっちが惹くから
I'll draw you in completely,
エンタースペースでエスケープ
so escape through the enter space
さぁ！
Come on!
ここは0と1の楽園
This is the paradise of 0s and 1s
さぁ！
Come on!
広く深い世界から見つければ全て
If you find it from the wide and deep world, it's everything
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come here, come here
酸いも甘いも頂きます
I'll take the bittersweet and the sweet
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手取って
Surfin' Surfin', taking hand in hand
白昼夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Let's dance the night away in a daydream
ハイ！ ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
ハイハイ！
Hai hai!
みんなありがとー！
Thank you, everyone!
攻略電子の海は今日も
In the conquerable electronic sea, today too,
赤青緑でとにかく一杯一杯
it's full to the brim with red, blue, and green
悠々自適のテルライトで
With a leisurely tell-light,
お待ちかねのいつもの開始中
the long-awaited usual is starting now
そんなこんな どんなもんな あんなような事
This and that, how is it, that kind of thing,
下らなさこそが至福の鍵でしょ
triviality is the key to bliss, isn't it?
のんびりでぐだらで あんな事行こう
Let's go lazily and idly like that,
コマンドでエディットでレスポンス
with commands, edits, and responses
さぁ！
Come on!
ここは雲の向こうの未来
This is the future beyond the clouds
さぁ！
Come on!
狭く暗いブルースじゃ物足りないの
The narrow and dark blues just aren't enough
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come here, come here
酸いも甘いも忘れてさ
forgetting both the bittersweet and the sweet
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手取って
Surfin' Surfin', taking hand in hand
白昼夢中にするわ 覚えてて
I'll make you daydream, remember that
せーの！
Ready, go!
サーフィン！
Surfin'!
もっと！
More!
サーフィン サーフィン！
Surfin' Surfin'!
もっと！
More!
サーフィン サーフィン！
Surfin' Surfin'!
エレクトリカル・サーフィン サーフィン
Electrical Surfin' Surfin'
こちらを見て見て
Look here, look here
空に輝く軌跡の輪
The ring of tracks shining in the sky
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手取って
Surfin' Surfin', taking hand in hand
ウェルカム・チュムチュムで
With a welcome chuum-chuum,
飛べ！
Fly!
飛べ！ 飛べ！ 飛べ！
Fly! Fly! Fly!
サーフィン サーフィン
Surfin' Surfin'
こちらに来て来て
Come here, come here
酸いも甘いも頂きます
I'll take the bittersweet and the sweet
サーフィン サーフィン 手と手取って
Surfin' Surfin', taking hand in hand
白昼夢中で踊り明かしましょう
Let's dance the night away in a daydream
ハイ！ ハイ！
Hai! Hai!
ハイハイ！
Hai hai!
はい！ということで、ありがとうございましたー！
Yes! And with that, thank you very much!
いやあ、盛り上がる曲！
Wow, what an exciting song!
いっぱい踊れるようなイメージで、
With the image of being able to dance a lot,
新衣装作ったので、
I designed the new outfit,
次のゲストパートでもどんな感じになるかなっていうのを見ていこうと思います。
so I'm looking forward to seeing how it looks in the next guest part too.
次が最後のゲストパートです。
The next one is the last guest part.
告知を見てくれた人なら分かるよね？
If you saw the announcement, you know who it is, right?
この人たちです！
It's these people!
儒烏風亭らでん 轟はじめ
Juufuutei Raden, Todoroki Hajime
シネマ
Cinema
誰もが突然に始まった
Everyone started suddenly
でたらめなシナリオの上で
on a haphazard scenario
それは映画のような まるで映画のような
It's like a movie, just like a movie
どこにでもあるストーリー
a story found anywhere
間違いだらけの道のりだ
It's a path full of mistakes
丸つけられるのは幾つだ
How many can be marked correct?
何が良くないのか どこが良くないのか
What's not good, where is it not good?
そこまで教えてくれよ
Tell me that much
明け方の妄想中な逃避行と
An escape during a dawn delusion
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
and playing mistaken hero
もう渋滞してんだ
It's already congested,
どうしようもこうしようもないよな
there's nothing that can be done, right?
こんなはずじゃなかったよなって
It wasn't supposed to be like this
どんなはずだったんだよなって
How was it supposed to be?
思えば思うほど
The more I think about it,
いやこれじゃないない、塩梅悪いよな
no, this isn't it, it's a bad balance
...向いてないない
...not suited for this.
今すぐ辞めてしまえば
If I just quit right now.
そりゃないない　いつになれば僕は
That's not right, when will I ever...
主役になれるのだろう
...become the main character?
足りなくなるたびに笑ったり
Laughing every time things fall short,
上手にも近付いては泣いたり
Or crying as I get closer to those better than me.
期待するほどでもなくガッカリ
I'm not even expecting much, but I'm still disappointed.
責めることすらできずウンザリ
Fed up because I can't even blame anyone.
燦々と輝く街の灯り
The city lights shine brilliantly,
散々だって顔の通り縋り
Clinging on, looking as miserable as I feel.
始めるなら今、そうだろ
If I'm going to start, it's now, right?
またやろう　やろう　やろう
Let's do it again, and again, and again.
これじゃないない　余り悪いような
This isn't it, it feels like it's too bad.
向いてないない
I'm not suited for this.
今すぐ辞めてしまえば
If I just quit right now.
でも何万回と繰り返した
But after repeating this tens of thousands of times,
明日に期待してしまおうか
Maybe I'll start expecting something from tomorrow.
明け方の空想、基調の逃避行
Dawn-time fantasies, a fundamental escape,
勘違いの英雄ごっこ
Playing hero in my own delusions.
もう渋滞してんだ、どうしようもこうしようもないような
It's already congested, like there's nothing that can be done.
あの頃は確かにあったんだ
Back then, it definitely existed.
描き出したものがあったんだ
The things I had envisioned.
いつの間にか僕は
Before I knew it, I...
誰もが突然に始まった
Everyone suddenly began,
デタラメなシナリオの上で
On a nonsensical script.
何かを演じるの？
Am I performing something?
誰かを演じるの？
Am I performing as someone?
そんなわけないだろ
There's no way that's true.
まだこれじゃ　まだここじゃ
Not like this, not here yet,
終わりじゃないから
Because it's not the end.
向いてないない
I'm not suited for this.
なら書き換えてしまえよ
Then just rewrite it!
ほら無い無い、いつになればきっと
See, there's nothing, surely when the time comes,
主役は僕だけだろ
I'll be the only main character.
いつの日かバイバイ
One day, bye-bye,
終わりは来るから
Because the end will come.
拍手喝采、笑顔でアンコール
A standing ovation, an encore with a smile.
変えたい未来はここにあった
The future I wanted to change was right here.
思うままに好きなように
Just as I wish, however I like.
これはそうだ
This is, indeed,
底辺から駆け上がった
Rising up from the very bottom,
映画のようなストーリー
A story just like a movie.
はい！ということで、最後のゲストは、はじめちゃんと、
Yes! So, our final guests are Hajime-chan and...
らでんちゃんの、らでんはじコンビ！
...Raden-chan, the Radenhaji duo!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ボンボン！ボラ！おはまち！こんはじめ！鳥獣戯画の番長、轟はじめっちょ！
Bon-bon! Bola! Ohamachi! Konhajime! The boss of the Choujuu Giga, Todoroki Hajime-cho!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい！重低音...ちょっと待って！全然見えない。
Yes! Deep bass... Wait a sec! I can't see anything.
重低音、らでんでございます！
I'm Juufuutei Raden!
イェーイ！
Yay!
そして、そら先輩、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
And Sora-senpai, happy birthday!
おめでとうございます！
Congratulations!
そして新衣装、おめでとうございます！
And congratulations on your new outfit!
え、ぜひちょっとスクショなど撮りたいな、って思うんですけど。
Um, I'd definitely like to take some screenshots.
あ、じゃあポーズを...。
Oh, then, how about a pose...
ちょっと待って、カメラ...。
Wait a minute, the camera...
なんで、そら先輩が撮られる方...。
Why is it that Sora-senpai is the one being photographed...
あ、カメラマンになるんじゃないの？
Oh, aren't you going to be the photographer?
違う違う違う...。
No, no, no...
可愛いなー。
So cute.
じゃあはじめから、ポーズして。なんか、しちゃったり...。
Then let's have a pose from the start. Like, do something...
それは先輩の「テクティーポーズ」。
That's senpai's 'tecty pose'.
テクティーポーズみたいな。おー、いいですね！
Like a tecty pose. Oh, that's good!
おー、いいですね！このラインがいいですね、このラインが。
Oh, that's nice! This line is great, this line right here.
シンプルな衣装だからこそ映えるね。
It really stands out because it's such a simple outfit.
お、ポージング。この絶対領域の部分とかも...。
Oh, the posing. Even the absolute territory part...
お、いいですねー！あー！あー！
Oh, that's great! Ah! Ah!
すごい！なんか、なんだろ、ベルトみたいな感じになってて。めちゃめちゃ素敵ですね！
Amazing! It's like, I don't know, it's got a belt-like feel to it. It's so lovely!
素敵や。
It is lovely.
じゃあちょっとらでんからも、ちょっと見返り美人のポーズなんて、してもらってもいいですか？
Then, could I also ask for a 'mikaeri bijin' pose from you?
お、呼んだ？
Oh, did you call me?
可愛いー！！
So cute!!
これには菱川師宣もびっくりですよね！
Even Hishikawa Moronobu would be surprised by this!
菱川師宣の人だ！
It's the Hishikawa Moronobu person!
見返り美人の人！
The 'mikaeri bijin' person!
すごーい！
Amazing!
めちゃめちゃいい。素敵やー！
It's so good. It's lovely!
みんなスクショできた？できたかな？
Did everyone get their screenshots? I wonder if they did.
おー！なんか髪型も新鮮で。
Oh! And the hairstyle is so fresh too.
脇も見えちゃった！
I even saw your armpits!
脇が見えちゃった！
Saw the armpits!
脇がー！あー！あー！そら先輩の脇がー！
The armpits! Ah! Ah! Sora-senpai's armpits!
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
見えちゃった！
I saw them!
めちゃめちゃいい！
So good!
イェーイ！
Yay!
え、じゃあ三人でも撮りたい。
Oh, then I want to take one with all three of us.
いいですか？
Is that okay?
じゃーん！
Ta-da!
おー！なんか、髪型、ショート同士。
Oh! We all have short hairstyles.
あ、本当だ！
Oh, you're right!
お揃い！
Matching!
なんかいいな、いいな、いいな。
This is nice, so nice.
服装、モノトーン同士。
And we're all in monotone outfits.
良いね！
Nice!
そらちゃん、一人だけ季節感バグってる人がいますよ。
Sora-chan, there's one person whose sense of season is totally bugged.
そんなことない、そんなことない！春、夏、秋、冬ってことで！
No, no, it's not like that! It's like spring, summer, autumn, and winter!
あ、ちょうどいい！
Ah, just right!
ちょうどいい、確かに。
Just right, indeed.
エッチやん。
It's sexy.
というわけで、二人と一緒に歌えてとっても嬉しかったし、
Anyway, I was very happy to be able to sing with you two,
これからも仲良くしてほしいよ！
and I hope we can continue to be friends!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please do!
ありがとうございました。皆様お邪魔しました。ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much. Sorry for the intrusion. Thank you.
失礼します。
Excuse us.
じゃあ、我々は。
Well then, we'll be off.
ではまた皆さん。
See you again, everyone.
その去り方は斬新すぎる。
That's way too original of an exit.
あん肝の中に消えてっちゃったよ。
They disappeared into Ankimo.
わー！
Wow!
ということで、ライブも終盤に近づいてきましたが、
And so, the live is nearing its end,
最後まで盛り上がっていこう！
but let's keep the excitement going until the very end!
次の曲を聴いてください。
Please listen to the next song.
UNDEAD。
UNDEAD.
UNDEAD
悩める人よ
O troubled soul
人なら誰も彼も
As any human would
絶えず目指せよ 生きている証へ
Keep aiming for the proof of life
目を逸らした過去も
Even the past you turned away from
退屈な未来も
And the boring future
カウンセリング やれやれ
Counseling, oh boy
古今東西 ピース ピース
Everywhere, peace peace
UNDEAD / 作詞・作曲：Ayase
UNDEAD / Lyrics & Music: Ayase
ねえねえねえ
Hey hey hey
何だかどうして
Somehow, why
戦ってるような 気がするの
Does it feel like I'm fighting
誰にも見せたくもない
I don't want to show anyone
過去の自分 自分 自分
My past self, self, self
もうとっくに死んでる
Already long dead
ごめんね 亡霊と対決したいけれど
Sorry, I want to face the ghost, but
痛い 記憶の奥
It hurts, deep in the memories
三昧 もういないのに
Absorbed, even though they're no longer there
あれ そっちがいいのにね
Oh, that one would be better
唆されてるのは 今の自分
The one being instigated is my current self
ナンセンス 消えないレッテル
Nonsense, the label won't disappear
一生 弱 コンプレックス
A lifelong weak complex
乗り移られてるみたい 巻き付いたまま
Like I'm possessed, still wrapped around me
まだ離れない 在りし日の自分
Still won't leave, my past self
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない おまじないの連鎖
Not dead, a chain of spells
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To live is to keep changing
不遇に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't be content with misfortune
幸せになろうとしてんだよ
I'm trying to be happy
この世、この世は ピカピカ ファンタジー
This world, this world is a shiny fantasy
次は 鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Next, will it be a demon or a snake?
出合って合って やっと始まる物語
Meeting and matching, the story finally begins
さあ 人化け物語 拡大ピース ピース
Now, the human-monster story, expanding peace peace
何だかどうして みんな良い子になっちゃったの
Somehow, why has everyone become such good kids?
傲慢でいたいのさ 強欲な気がして
I want to be arrogant, feeling greedy
もうずいぶん言ってる 気疲れテンパって食傷
I've said it for a long time, exhausted, panicking, fed up
素敵な出来事の 気配もない
No sign of wonderful events
三昧 詰んだ経験値が 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
Absorbed, the piled up EXP, the skeletal myths and boring evolution
飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった なんて 滞っていくガイダンス
I'm tired of it, I'm used to it, such stagnating guidance
震えるコンプライアンス 淘汰されてくみたい
Trembling compliance, like being selected
すいすいすいして
Swish swish swish
あれも これも どれも 同じ味がする
That, this, which, they all taste the same
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない おまじないの連鎖
Not dead, a chain of spells
いつの世も過去も未来も 今にあるんだ
Every era, past and future, is in the now
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the fact of living with honesty
目指せハッピーエンド
Aim for a happy ending
UNDEAD
死んじゃいない お前に似てるんだ
Not dead, it resembles you
幸せを諦めてしまう人であれ
Be someone who gives up on happiness
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just being used to pain and enduring it
死んでるのと同然 屍のUNDEAD
Is the same as being dead, the corpse's UNDEAD
UNDEAD
悩める人よ 人なら誰も彼も
O troubled soul, as any human would
絶えず目指せよ 生きている証へ
Keep aiming for the proof of life
不遇に浸るも 幸せになるのも
Whether to indulge in misfortune or to become happy
そう全部全部 お前だ
Yes, all of it is you
古今東西一切合切死ねば諸共ピース ピース
Everything everywhere, if you die together, peace peace
人ならざる所に
In a place where one is not human
集まれ良い子もイケナイ子も
Gather, good kids and bad kids alike
化け物ばかりの物語
A story full of monsters
ピース ピース
Peace peace
はい、ということで、UNDEAD、歌いましたー！
Yes, and so, that was UNDEAD!
今回も振り付けを作っていただいて、頑張って歌いましたが、みんなどうだったかな？
I had the choreography made again and did my best singing it. How was it, everyone?
どうだったかな？いい感じだったかな？
How was it? Was it good?
いや、ちょっと細かくて難しかったんですけど、でも楽しく歌えたし、
Well, it was a bit detailed and difficult, but I enjoyed singing it,
みんながね、見てくれててとっても嬉しいです。
and I'm very happy that everyone was watching.
というわけで、まだ最後にお披露目はあるんですが、その前にお知らせが二つあります。
So, there's still one last reveal, but before that, I have two announcements.
まずはこちら！
First, this!
ときのそら誕生日記念2025グッズです！イェーイ！
Tokino Sora Birthday Memorial 2025 Goods! Yay!
ときのそら 誕生日記念 2025
Tokino Sora Birthday Memorial 2025
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
イエーイって言ってくれてる気がする。
I feel like everyone's saying "Yay!"
順番に紹介していくよ。まずはこちら！
I'll introduce them in order. First, this one!
「夢のそばワンマン」ファブリックポスター。
"At the Side of a Dream One-Man" fabric poster.
私がダンスしてるワンシーンを切り取った布製のファブリックポスターです。
This is a fabric poster capturing a scene of me dancing.
紙のポスターとは違って折れたりする心配もないですし、
Unlike paper posters, you don't have to worry about it folding,
長く飾ってくれるかなということで、余白のサイズに合わせて折り畳んだりして飾ることもできると思うので、
and since you'll likely display it for a long time, you can fold it to fit your space.
ぜひぜひみんな部屋に飾ってね。
So please, everyone, display it in your room.
続いてはこちら！
Next up is this!
そらとおそろい2wayネックレス。
Matching-with-Sora 2-way necklace.
今回の新衣装でもしてるネックレスのおそろっちが作りたいなと思って、おそろっちのものを用意しました。
I wanted to make a matching version of the necklace I'm wearing with this new outfit.
ただね、ネックレスはしないよっていう人のために、チャーム部分を取り外しすることができる2way仕様になってまして、
For those who don't wear necklaces, the charm is removable, making it a 2-way design.
痛バとかバッグとかにワンポイントでも付けて一緒におそろっちっていう風にできるようにしました。
You can attach it to an itabag or any bag as an accent so we can still match.
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
そらのバンダナハンカチ。
Sora's bandana handkerchief.
イエーイ！
Yay!
おそろい柄のハンカチ。今回はみんなとおそろっちっていうのをテーマに作ってみました。
This matching-pattern handkerchief was made with the theme of "matching with everyone."
シンプルなデザインなので日常でも使えますし、ロゴも入ってるのでとっても可愛いかなと思います。
It's a simple design for everyday use, and it has a logo, making it very cute.
シンプルでいつも持ち歩きやすく、でもおそろいにもできる。
It's simple, easy to carry, and allows us to match.
みんなバンダナはしないかなと思ったのでハンカチにしてみました。
I thought maybe not everyone wears bandanas, so I went with a handkerchief.
みんなで私を持ち歩いてね。
Please carry a little piece of me with you.
そして続いてはこちら！
And next up is this!
いつも一緒おでかけぬいバッグ。
Always-Together Outing Plushie Bag.
こちらはパーカー衣装の私が載ったぬんぬん型のポーチを開けると、
When you open the Nun-Nun pouch featuring me in my hoodie outfit,
あんきも柄のバッグが出てくるぬいバッグということで、
an Ankimo-patterned bag comes out of this "plushie bag."
ぬいぐるみのキーホルダーの感覚で一緒に歩くこととか、バッグにつけること、痛バみたいに作ることもできるし、
You can carry it like a plushie keyholder, attach it to a bag, or even make an itabag.
持ち運べるし、グッズとか買いすぎちゃったーって時に、入らないなーって時にちょっと出して使えたりもすると思うので、
It's portable, so if you buy too much merch, you can pull this out to use it.
ぜひぜひこれはずっと出してみたかったグッズなので、みんなに見てもらえると嬉しいです。
This is a product I've wanted to release for a long time, so I'm happy to share it.
そして最後はこちら！
And finally, this one!
ボイス。シチュエーションボイス「ライブの後で」。
Voice packs. Situation Voice: "After the Live."
ちょっとおちゃめな私とこれからに向けた意気込みを語るかっこいい私の両方が楽しめるボイスです。
Enjoy both a playful me and a cool me talking about my future goals.
そして今回はフルセットの特典が2つあるよ。
And this time, there are two full set bonuses.
まずはこちら！
First, this one!
ときのそら直筆サイン＋箔押し複製メッセージ。
Tokino Sora handwritten signature + foil-stamped duplicate message.
今回は数量限定なしでやるので、ぜひ、皆さんたくさんたくさんサイン書かせてください。
We're doing this without quantity limits, so please let me sign a whole lot!
心を込めて全部書くから、ぜひぜひいっぱい応募してね。
I'll sign every single one with all my heart, so please apply for many!
そしてもう一つの特典はこちら！
And the other bonus is this!
hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAMEで使用できるPRカードが1枚つきます。
It includes one PR card for use in the hololive OFFICIAL CARD GAME.
フルセットを購入した人だけの特別な推しホロメンカードです。
This is a special Oshi Holomen card only for full set purchasers.
まだ遊んだことないよーって人も、ホームページや遊び方を確認できるから、ぜひチェックしてね。
Even if you haven't played, you can check the website for details and rules.
これでみんな勝ってくれるだろうな。勝ってくれよ！
I'm sure everyone will win with this. Please win!
ということで以上、誕生日グッズでした。みんなよろしくね。
So, those were the birthday goods. I'm counting on you all.
そして2つ目のお知らせは、なんと！
And for the second announcement, amazingly!
今日かな？の0時にデジタル配信が始まりました「Swallow Tail」のミュージックビデオ、
The MV for "Swallow Tail," which was released digitally at midnight today,
なんとこの後、プレミア公開かな！
will amazingly have a premiere release right after this!
みんなに感謝の気持ちを込めてMVを用意しておきました。
I've prepared this MV with all my gratitude for everyone.
ぜひぜひ皆さんMVでも私の曲聞いてください！
So please, everyone, listen to my song in the MV too!
これが嬉しい告知だよ。
This is the happy announcement.
爽やかな感じで感謝を込めつつ、ちょっと切ない歌詞とかもあったりするので、MV発表がありましょうということで。
It's a refreshing song filled with gratitude, with some bittersweet lyrics.
この後21時15分からの予定なんですけど、ギリギリかもしれない。
It's scheduled for 21:15 after this, but it might be very close.
明言は21時半からになります。
To be certain, it'll start at 21:30.
よろしくお願いします。
I hope you enjoy it.
というわけで、その曲、最後に聞きたくない？
So, don't you want to hear that song at the end?
初めて生で歌います。
I'll be singing it live for the first time.
この曲で締めたいと思います。聞いてください。Swallow Tail。
I'd like to end with this song. Please listen: Swallow Tail.
Swallow Tail
作詩・作曲・編曲：buzzG
Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: buzzG
澄み渡る青はいつも
The clear blue is always...
始まりを強く照らすから
...strongly illuminating the beginning.
本当は震えている
Actually, I'm shaking.
手足が隠せないよ
I can't hide my trembling hands and feet.
物語の先はどう？
What's ahead in the story?
君なら何色で描く？
What color would you paint it with?
噎せ返った日のこと
About the day I choked up...
辞められなかった日のこと
...and the day I couldn't quit.
燕みたいに早く
If only I could fly as fast...
飛べたならいいのに
...as a swallow.
もう何もいらないから
I don't need anything else anymore...
忘れさせないから
...because I won't let you forget.
どこまでも遠くへと
To wherever, far away...
このまま手を繋いで
...holding hands just like this.
向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
As if swimming through tears in a headwind...
淡い闇を越えて
...crossing the faint darkness.
歪な翼で踊ろうよ
Let's dance with our distorted wings...
無限の夏の空へ
...towards the infinite summer sky.
みんなありがとう！
Thank you, everyone!
失くした鍵は見つかった
The lost key was finally found.
燃えるゴミの日に出しちゃった
I accidentally put it out with the burnable trash.
いつのまにか惹き付けた
Before I knew it, I was drawn to...
君のスペシャルな夢の種
...the seed of your special dream.
子供みたいに青く
If only I could wish for it...
願えたらいいのに
...with the innocence of a child.
気が付けば檻の中で
Before I realized it, I was in a cage.
ありがとー！
Thank you!
胸の隅で痛んで
Aching in the corner of my chest...
泣くのはきっと大事なものだから
...crying is because it's something important.
間違っても彷徨っても
Even if I make mistakes or wander...
離さないでいよう
...let's never let go.
空の果て、群青の
Looking beyond the ultramarine...
その先を見つめて
...at the edge of the sky.
飛びたいの、この命懸けて
I want to fly, even if it costs my life.
もう何もいらないから
I don't need anything else anymore...
忘れさせないから
...because I won't let you forget.
どこまでも遠くへと
To wherever, far away...
ありのまま紡いで
...spinning it just as it is.
向かい風に涙を泳ぐように
As if swimming through tears in a headwind...
淡い闇を越えて
...crossing the faint darkness.
歪な翼でいよう、行こう
Let's stay with our distorted wings and go...
無限の夏の空へ
...towards the infinite summer sky.
今日見に来てくれてありがとう！
Thank you for coming to see me today!
とってもとっても嬉しかったし、
I was very, very happy,
ちょっとヘンな嬉しさだね！
and it's a bit of a weird happiness!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you very much!
ファンクラのアフターライブもメン限だけど、よかったら来てね！
The fan club after-live is members-only, but please join if you'd like!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!